# **Burak Kiran**

**Computer Scientist** 

Webpage: https://kiran1226.github.io/devportfolio/

I am a young dedicated and enthusiastic Computer Scientist specializing in Data Science and Data Analytics. With a strong educational background, including a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from Technische Universität Berlin and currently pursuing a Master's degree in Information Systems Management, I am well-equipped to tackle complex data challenges.

# **Work Experience**

MyToys Group, Berlin - Process Automation Engineer

12.2021 - now

- Job: Working Student
- Main task: Automation of internal "Product Management Excellence" team workflows
- Software Model: Scrum Model with 2 week sprints (Jira)
- Automating workflows by creating webapps and connecting to different API's with python (example: Jira)
- Filtering and cleaning data with python in excel and csv format
- Web Scraping to get information about products
- CHecking data correctness with SQL and Python
- Focussed Python Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Requests,
   Tkinter, BeautifulSoup, Django, Flask, SQLAlchemy

GetHenry, Berlin - Data Collection and Reporting

11.2021 - 12.2021

- Job: Minijob
- Entering bicycle information to google sheets (Data Entry)
- Checking whether each bike has the correct information (Data Control)
- Gained skill: **Detail Orientation**

Nutricia GmbH, Erlangen - Company Overview Intern

08.2018 - 08.2018

- Visiting different departments and understanding the big picture
- Recording the complaints through SAP

#### Contact

https://kiran1226.github.io/devportfolio/

+49 176 204 05845 burakkiran1226@gmail.com Beuthstraβe 15, 10117 Berlin, Germany

### **Spoken Languages**

English (C1)

German (C2)

Turkish (C2)

### **Skills (Stars represent years)**

Algorithms and Data Structures: \* \* \*

Analysis and Linear Algebra: \*

API Usage: \*\*

Assembly: \*

Automation: \* \*

C: \*

Data Analysis / Visualisation: \*

Flask \*\*

Git: \* \* \*

HTML: \*\*\*

Java: \*\*\*

JavaScript: \* \* \*

Jupiter: \*\*

PowerBI \*

Probability and statistics: \*

Python: \* \* \*

## **Projects**

## More projects are in explained in:

https://kiran1226.github.io/devportfolio/

#### Machine Learning (Group Project)

04.2023 - now, Berlin

- Look at the use cases of unsupervised learning
- try to implement different algorithms
- Used Python Libraries: Torch, Numpy, Torchvision

# Visual Perception Bachelor Thesis (Individual Project)

10.2022 - 03.2023, Berlin

- Analyzing and Plotting different experiment data from literature
- Predicting a new experiment results through the analyzed data with the help of linear regression
- Used Python Libraries: Pandas, numpy, scipy, math, seaborn, matplotlib, os

#### Data Science (Group Project)

04.2021 - 08.2021, Berlin

- Aiming to guess songs future trajectory in Billboard 100 by analyzing the past weeks Billboard 100 place
- Aiming to answer the question: How can a song stay the longest in Billboard 100?
- Used Technologies: matplotlib, seaborn, numpy, pandas, time

# Scientific Programming with Python (Individual Project)

04.2020 - 08.2020, Berlin

- 6 Mini school projects
- Goal: Learn implementing Linear Algebra with python

R: \*

SQL: \*\*

Scientific Research: \*\*

Tableau \*\*

VS code: \*\*\*

#### **Education**

### Technische Universität Berlin, Berlin - M.Sc.

2022 - now, Berlin

Study Of Information Systems Management

### Technische Universität Berlin, Berlin - B.Sc.

2018 - 2023, Berlin Study Of Computer Science

# Deutsche Schule, Istanbul - High School.

2013 - 2018, Istanbul

Study Of Computer Science

#### **Certificates:**

#### **IBM Data Science Course**

A 5 month Data Science Course to train candidates on a "Junior Data Scientist Level". Here is the link for a better description:

https://www.coursera.org/professiona l-certificates/ibm-data-science

#### **Hobbies:**

Beach Volleyball

F1

Traveling